{"Topic": "Freedom Fighters", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Who of the following was considered by the British to be The Father of Indian Unrest?", "op1": "Gopal Krishna Gokhale", "op2": "Lokmanya Tilak", "op3": "Lala Lajpat Rai", "op4": "Madan Mohan Malaviya", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who succeeded Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel as the 2nd Home minister of India?", "op1": "Abul Kalam Azad", "op2": "Madan Mohan Malaviya", "op3": "C Rajagopalachari", "op4": "None of the above", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Gyan Prasarak Mandali, an organization dedicated to the education of the adult was formed by \u2013", "op1": "G K Gokhale", "op2": "M M Malviya", "op3": "Dadabhai Naoroji", "op4": "Lokmanya Tilak", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which language was Kesari, a newspaper started by Bal Gangadhar Tilak published?", "op1": "Marathi", "op2": "Hindi", "op3": "English", "op4": "Both (B) and (C)", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Hitavada, the newspaper started by Gopal Krishna Gokhale in 1911 was initially published from \u2013", "op1": "Mumbai", "op2": "Pune", "op3": "Sholapur", "op4": "Nagpur"}, {"Question": "Do or Die was one of the most powerful slogans of India\u2019s freedom struggle. Who gave it?", "op1": "Gandhiji", "op2": "J. L. Nehru", "op3": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak", "op4": "Subhash Chandra Bose", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Dadabhai Naoroji was the first Indian to be appointed as a Professor at Elphinstone College in", "op1": "Mumbai", "op2": "London", "op3": "Delhi", "op4": "Stuttgart", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who founded the Deccan Education Society to impart teachings about India culture to India\u2019s youth?", "op1": "Dadabhai Naoroji", "op2": "Lokmanya Tilak", "op3": "Motilal Nehru", "op4": "C Rajagopalachari", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following newspapers was started by Motilal Nehru in 1919?", "op1": "Voice of India", "op2": "The Leader", "op3": "Young India", "op4": "Independent", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Three of the following were awarded the Bharat Ratna in the same year. Who was awarded much later?", "op1": "C Rajagopalachari", "op2": "S Radhakrishnan", "op3": "Abul Kalam Azad", "op4": "CV Raman", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which year was the Banaras Hindu University established by Pt Madan Mohan Malviya?", "op1": "1914", "op2": "1916", "op3": "1919", "op4": "1920", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who was the chairman of All Parties Conference which put up a draft constitution recommending full dominion status for India?", "op1": "Motilal Nehru", "op2": "Dadabhai Naoroji", "op3": "Lala Lajpat Rai", "op4": "Rajagopalachari", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In 1923, who of the following became the youngest person to be elected the President of the Indian National Congress?", "op1": "Motilal Nehru", "op2": "Abul Kalam Azad", "op3": "Lala Lajpat Rai", "op4": "M M Malaviya", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who was elected the first President of All India Trade Union Congress in 1920?", "op1": "Gopal Krishna Gokhale", "op2": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak", "op3": "Lala Lajpat Rai", "op4": "Dadabhai Naoroji", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In 1905, who founded the Servants of India Society, aimed at promoting education, sanitation, health care as well as fighting social evils?", "op1": "Lokmanya Tilak", "op2": "G K Gokhale", "op3": "Frontier Gandhi", "op4": "Lala Lajpat Rai", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Match the parties with their founders", "op1": "1-c; 2-b; 3-c", "op2": "1-b; 2-a; 3-c", "op3": "1-a; 2-c; 3-b", "op4": "1-c; 2-a; 3-b", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who was one of the main organizers of the Dharasana Satyagraha in 1931, which was a non-violent raid on Dharasana Salt Works?", "op1": "Madan M Malaviya", "op2": "Lokmanya Tilak", "op3": "Abul Kalam Azad", "op4": "C Rajagopalachari", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "From which place did Madan Mohan Malaviya publish his famous newspaper The Leader?", "op1": "Allahabad", "op2": "Banaras", "op3": "Aligarh", "op4": "Delhi", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Whose death coincided with the launch of the Non-cooperation Movement in 1920?", "op1": "Dadabhai  Naoroji", "op2": "Lokmanya Tilak", "op3": "GK Gokhale", "op4": "Motilal Nehru", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "After the Bardoli Satyagraha, the title of \u2018Sardar\u2019 to Vallabhbhai Patel was given by", "op1": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "op2": "Motilal Nehru", "op3": "Mahatma Gandhi", "op4": "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "With which of the following leaders is Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel equated?", "op1": "Martin Luther", "op2": "Bismarck", "op3": "Cavour", "op4": "Garibaldi", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Aruna Asaf Ali was associated with which one of the following?", "op1": "Bardoli Satyagraha", "op2": "Civil Disobedience Movement", "op3": "Khilafat Movement", "op4": "Quit India Movement", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The Home Rule League was started by", "op1": "M. K. Gandhi", "op2": "B. G. Tilak", "op3": "Ranade", "op4": "Veer Savarkar", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following leaders was popularly known as Lokhitwadi?", "op1": "Gopal Krishna Gokhale", "op2": "Gopal Hari Deshmukh", "op3": "Pherozshah Mehta", "op4": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who among the following formed a party named as \u2018Forward Bloc\u2019?", "op1": "Subhash Chandra Bose", "op2": "Sardar Bhagat Singh", "op3": "Chandrashekhar Azad", "op4": "J. L. Nehru", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who was the first Indian lady to preside over the Congress?", "op1": "Raj Kumari Amrit Kaur", "op2": "Annie Besant", "op3": "Vijayalakshmi Pandit", "op4": "Sarojini Naidu", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who said \"You give me blood, I will give you freedom\"?", "op1": "Mahatma Gandhi", "op2": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak", "op3": "Subhash Chandra Bose", "op4": "Bhagat Singh", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "One time associate of Mahatma Gandhi, broke off from him and launched a radical movement called \u2018self-respect movement\u2019 Who was he?", "op1": "P. Thyagaraja Shetti", "op2": "Chhatrapati Maharaj", "op3": "E. V. Ramaswamy Naickar", "op4": "Jyotirao Govindrao Phule"}, {"Question": "ated pages"}, {"Question": "s on British Governor Generals"}, {"Question": "s on First War of Indian Independence"}, {"Question": "s on Places during Freedom Struggle"}, {"Question": "s on Indian Revolutionaries"}, {"Question": "- British Governor Generals"}]}